# TARIKUL ISLAM

House# 234/1/3, Haji Joynab Tower (5D), Vhuiyapara, Meradia, Khilgaon, Dhaka-1219, Bangladesh.

Contact: +88 01912287111

Email: islm90@gmail.com

StackOverflow: <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/3278789/tarikul05">http://stackoverflow.com/users/3278789/tarikul05</a>

Blog: <a href="https://medium.com/@tarikul05">https://medium.com/@tarikul05</a>

Website: www.tarikul.com

Skype: tarikul05

#### **SUMMARY**

More than 9years of real time experience in the software industry, thinker, researcher, inventor, creative leader specializing in all areas of Web Application development. Key expertise is on software development, software architecture, Restful API development and database design. Specially worked on number of small ERP project with MVC Architecture. Having excellent knowledge of MVC Architecture.

### **FOCUSED KEYWORD**

Laravel, CakePHP, Ruby On Rails, RestFul-API, React-Native, DevOps CD/CI, Amazon Web Service, LAMP Stack, Agile, Jenkins, Docker, Mobile Apps

#### **KEY RESPONSIBILITES**

- Ability to work multiple projects at a time, Work under tight timeframes with good organizing skills.
- Ability to address and quickly fix HTML, CSS and scripting compatibility issues.
- Good knowledge on writing complex database query, optimizing code & indexing.
- Ability to meet deadlines and achieve specified results.
- System design and project estimation according to agile method.
- Integrating 3rd Party Software through API, developing API based application.
- System design and project estimation according to agile method.

### **Most Noticeable Projects**

Technology	Description	Works
SaaS in PHP,	Blog Template Management System	Design and Development, new features
Next JS		implement
Ruby On Rails,	Wikiapp engine for API and admin panel	Design and Development
React JS		
React Native	WikiApps mobile application for IOS and Android	Design and Development
Ruby On Rails	eRecruitment system and Email Templating Tools	Design and Development
CakePHP	Dev central: Automate Task Management System	Design and Development



CakePHP	Bangladesh Railway Purchase Software (Inventory and Tender Management)	Design and Development
Flutter , Next,	Pacific apps (features development), Admin panel in	Mobile Apps, admin panel , API
Ruby On rails	Next JS, API in Ruby on Rails	
CakePHP	FireGuard – Automation of Guard Hiring System	Admin Dashboard, RESTfull API
Yii	SwipeShark – Mobile Apps	API part
Laravel as SaaS	TSO international	Admin panel, RESTfull API, Automations
		client site
Laravel	SpotLogin- Online Event management (French)	Design and development
Slim Framework	Near me	API development
EC-Cube	Tashirotoki - eCommerce CMS (Japanese)	
CakePHP	Automobiles service management (Custom ERP)	Design and Development Collaborate
CakePHP	Martex online business management ERP (Japan)	Collaborate in team
POP3, IMAP	Webening.com, Email API	Development
Core PHP/ TC-	Opensource Exam Solutions Customization for	
Exam	FTFL Project	
Core PHP	FileSharing Application	
Magento	E-commerce Shop	Customization and Development
CakePHP	Chefgenie Restaurant Directory	Collaborate in team
Laravel	College management system	Development Team member
Wordpress	Export –import plugins for JP clients	
CorePHP	DIU Alumni	Technical Lead and Development Member
Codelgniter	Khowab – Online store and Photo Contest Platform	Development, Image Processing, Security ensure
Wordpress	Mental Wisdom – Psychology Web portal	

# **Skill Matrix**

Technologies	Average	Good	Excellent
РНР			<b>√</b>
Frameworks			
Laravel			<b>√</b>
Ruby On Rails			<b>V</b>
CakePHP			<b>√</b>
Yii, Slim	<b>~</b>		
Zend Framework, Symfony	<b>~</b>		
Codeigniter	<b>~</b>		

CI Provisioning	DevOps				
Servitanagement		CI Provisioning		<b>√</b>	
Server Management		AWS Web Service			<b>✓</b>
Mazon Web Service, Amazon CLI					<b>√</b>
Amazon Web Service, Amazon CLI					
RESTFull API   <		Capistrano			✓
RESTFull API   <			p	,	,
Open Source	Amazon W	/eb Service, Amazon CLI			
Magento (E-commerce)	RESTFull	API			<b>~</b>
Magento (E-commerce)	Open Sou				
Cos Commerce / Zen Cart (E-commerce)		Wordpress			<b>√</b>
BC-Cube (Japanees E-commerce)		Magento (E-commerce)		<b>√</b>	
JavaScript Core		Os Commerce / Zen Cart (E-commerce)		<b>√</b>	
JavaScript Libraries		EC-Cube (Japanees E-commerce)		<b>√</b>	
JavaScript Libraries				k	<b>S</b>
Query	JavaScript	t Core			<b>✓</b>
Next JS	Java Scrip	ot Libraries			
Angular Js		jQuery			<b>✓</b>
NodeJS		Next JS			<b>√</b>
ReactJS		Angular Js	<b>~</b>		
AJAX HTML5  CSS2, CSS3  Responsive Web Design, Bootstrap   Database  MySQL  NoSql  Mongo DB, MSSQL  Firebase  Web Service		NodeJS		<b>√</b>	
AJAX  HTML5  CSS2, CSS3  Responsive Web Design, Bootstrap   Database  MySQL  NoSql  NoSql  Mongo DB, MSSQL  Firebase  Web Service		ReactJS		<b>√</b>	
AJAX  HTML5  CSS2, CSS3  Responsive Web Design, Bootstrap   Database  MySQL  NoSql  NoSql  Mongo DB, MSSQL  Firebase  Web Service					
CSS2, CSS3	AJAX				<b>✓</b>
Responsive Web Design, Bootstrap  Database  MySQL  NoSql  Mongo DB, MSSQL  Firebase  Web Service	HTML5				<b>✓</b>
Responsive Web Design, Bootstrap    Database	CSS2, CSS	53			<b>✓</b>
MySQL	Responsiv	ve Web Design, Bootstrap			<b>✓</b>
MySQL			•	•	
NoSql ✓  Mongo DB, MSSQL ✓  Firebase ✓  Web Service	Database				
Mongo DB, MSSQL  Firebase  ✓  Web Service		MySQL			<b>✓</b>
Firebase   Web Service		NoSql			<b>✓</b>
Web Service		Mongo DB, MSSQL		✓	
		Firebase			<b>√</b>
		1	i	<u> </u>	<u> </u>
REST, Swagger For API, SOAP ✓	Web Servi	ce			
		REST, Swagger For API, SOAP			<b>√</b>

	Payment API			✓
	AWS CLI, Bash programming,		<b>√</b>	
	ol.	4		
Developn	nent Tool			
	Sublime Text, VS code			<b>*</b>
	PHPStrom , NetBeans, Atom			<b>~</b>
Version C	Control			
	GIT & GITHUB			<b>~</b>
	Bitbucket, gitlab, Backlog,			<b>~</b>
		•		

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Leader & Project manager Jan 2020 – Present

Reivo Inc. (Japanese)

Senior Software Developer May 2017 – Dec 2019

Oceanize Bangladesh (Reivo japan )

Senior Software Engineer Sept 2016 – May 2017

NevadaSoft Bangladesh

Software Engineer May 2015 – Aug 30 2016

Optimal Track Automation & Engineering

Web Developer Jan 2014 – May 2015

Live Outsource Limited

# **OTHER WORKING EXPERIENCE**

2013-2015	2 Year	Trainer and course co-ordinator At Nester IT solutions (Web Development)
2010-2013	3 Year	Director Finance and System Engineer of <b>HR Group</b> . Also the presenter & Maintaining Good Communication with Clients.
2010	8 Month	Representative of 'Passion Developers'
2009-2010	6 Month	Working experience in 'Daily Vorer Daak' as Computer Operator
2007-2008	1 Year	Working experience in <b>National ID Card Project</b> as a 'Computer Operator & System Engineer'

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelors in Computer Science
Dhaka International University, Bangladesh

Jan 2010 - Dec 2013

HSC in Science Group

Matibhanga Degree College, Pirojpur, Bangladesh

2007 - 2009

### **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

ACM ICPC-2012 Asia Regional (Dhaka Site) Programming Contest

Venue: Radisson Blu Water Garden Hotel

Intra University Programming Contest

Venue: Dhaka International University

Result: 3rd Place

Intra University Programming Contest April, 2011

Venue: Dhaka International University

Result: 3rd Place

Attend in All University Math Olympiad 2010

Venue: East-West University

### LANGUAGE ABILITIES

English: Professional fluency (written and spoken) Bengali: Native fluency (written and spoken)

#### **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

Programming, Reading books, Watching Movie, Playing Football, Table tennis

### **Personal Information**

Name : Tarikul Islam

Father's Name : Ibrahim Shaikh

Mother's Name : Rumicha Begum

Date of Birth : 2<sup>nd</sup> February 1992

Nationality : Bangladeshi by birth

Religion : Islam
Marital Status : Married

Permanent Address : Vill+P.O: Matibhanga, P.S: Nazirpur District: Pirojpur

# Reference:

#### 1. A.T.M. Mahbubur Rahman

Chairman, Department of CSE
Dhaka International University
Contact:+88 01720557279
Email: mrrahmandiu@yahoo.com

#### 2. Mian Zadid Rusdid

CTO Live Outsource

Contact:+88 01675420232 Email: <a href="mailto:rusdid@gmail.com">rusdid@gmail.com</a>



<u>.</u>	
Signature	

November 2012

April, 2012